 const questionnaire = {
  questions: [
    {
      "question": "Who played the role of Vijay in the movie 'Sholay'?",
      "options": [
        "Amitabh Bachchan",
        "Shahrukh Khan",
        "Salman Khan",
        "Rajesh Khanna"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Amitabh Bachchan",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which movie featured the famous song 'Chaiyya Chaiyya'?",
      "options": [
        "Dil Se",
        "Kabhi Khushi Kabhie Gham",
        "Kuch Kuch Hota Hai",
        "Swades"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Dil Se",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which year was 'Mughal-e-Azam' released?",
      "options": ["1955", "1960", "1965", "1970"],
      "correctAnswer": "1960",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is known as the 'Tragedy King' of Bollywood?",
      "options": ["Dilip Kumar", "Raj Kapoor", "Dev Anand", "Guru Dutt"],
      "correctAnswer": "Dilip Kumar",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Bollywood actor starred in the Hollywood movie 'xXx: Return of Xander Cage'?",
      "options": [
        "Akshay Kumar",
        "Ranveer Singh",
        "Deepika Padukone",
        "Priyanka Chopra"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Deepika Padukone",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who composed the music for 'Lagaan'?",
      "options": [
        "A. R. Rahman",
        "Shankar-Ehsaan-Loy",
        "Vishal-Shekhar",
        "Pritam"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "A. R. Rahman",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which actress is known as the 'Queen of Bollywood'?",
      "options": [
        "Kareena Kapoor",
        "Kangana Ranaut",
        "Alia Bhatt",
        "Anushka Sharma"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Kangana Ranaut",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Bollywood film is inspired by the novel 'Five Point Someone'?",
      "options": ["3 Idiots", "Taare Zameen Par", "Dangal", "PK"],
      "correctAnswer": "3 Idiots",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who directed the film 'Kabhi Khushi Kabhie Gham'?",
      "options": [
        "Yash Chopra",
        "Karan Johar",
        "Sanjay Leela Bhansali",
        "Farah Khan"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Karan Johar",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the female lead in the movie 'Padmaavat'?",
      "options": [
        "Alia Bhatt",
        "Anushka Sharma",
        "Deepika Padukone",
        "Katrina Kaif"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Deepika Padukone",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which movie won the National Film Award for Best Feature Film in 2020?",
      "options": ["Gully Boy", "Article 15", "Asuran", "Marakkar: Lion of the Arabian Sea"],
      "correctAnswer": "Marakkar: Lion of the Arabian Sea",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which actor was known as 'The Angry Young Man' in Bollywood?",
      "options": [
        "Dharmendra",
        "Vinod Khanna",
        "Amitabh Bachchan",
        "Rajesh Khanna"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Amitabh Bachchan",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which movie featured the famous dialogue 'Mogambo khush hua'?",
      "options": ["Mr. India", "Sholay", "Deewar", "Don"],
      "correctAnswer": "Mr. India",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Bollywood film is based on the life of cricketer Mahendra Singh Dhoni?",
      "options": [
        "Dangal",
        "MS Dhoni: The Untold Story",
        "Sultan",
        "Bhaag Milkha Bhaag"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "MS Dhoni: The Untold Story",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who directed the film 'Bajrangi Bhaijaan'?",
      "options": [
        "Rajkumar Hirani",
        "Kabir Khan",
        "Sanjay Leela Bhansali",
        "Zoya Akhtar"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Kabir Khan",
      "category": "bollywood"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which dish is known as the staple food of South India?",
      "options": ["Biryani", "Dosa", "Samosa", "Pani Puri"],
      "correctAnswer": "Dosa",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which fruit is known as the 'King of Fruits'?",
      "options": ["Apple", "Banana", "Mango", "Grapes"],
      "correctAnswer": "Mango",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which cuisine is famous for sushi?",
      "options": ["Chinese", "Indian", "Japanese", "Thai"],
      "correctAnswer": "Japanese",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the main ingredient in guacamole?",
      "options": ["Tomato", "Avocado", "Lettuce", "Spinach"],
      "correctAnswer": "Avocado",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of pasta is shaped like little rice grains?",
      "options": ["Fusilli", "Penne", "Orzo", "Ravioli"],
      "correctAnswer": "Orzo",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the main ingredient of the drink known as 'Lassi'?",
      "options": ["Milk", "Butter", "Yogurt", "Cream"],
      "correctAnswer": "Yogurt",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Indian sweet is made from deep-fried chhena dough soaked in sugar syrup?",
      "options": ["Rasgulla", "Jalebi", "Gulab Jamun", "Barfi"],
      "correctAnswer": "Gulab Jamun",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the traditional accompaniment for sushi?",
      "options": ["Soy Sauce", "Vinegar", "Olive Oil", "Ketchup"],
      "correctAnswer": "Soy Sauce",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of rice is commonly used in biryani?",
      "options": ["Brown Rice", "Basmati Rice", "Jasmine Rice", "Sticky Rice"],
      "correctAnswer": "Basmati Rice",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of pizza is typically known for its thick, deep crust?",
      "options": ["Neapolitan", "Sicilian", "New York Style", "Chicago Style"],
      "correctAnswer": "Chicago Style",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is paneer commonly known as in English?",
      "options": ["Cottage Cheese", "Ricotta", "Mozzarella", "Parmesan"],
      "correctAnswer": "Cottage Cheese",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which country is the largest producer of coffee?",
      "options": ["Colombia", "Brazil", "Ethiopia", "Vietnam"],
      "correctAnswer": "Brazil",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the main ingredient in hummus?",
      "options": ["Lentils", "Chickpeas", "Kidney Beans", "Black Beans"],
      "correctAnswer": "Chickpeas",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which food item is often associated with Belgian cuisine?",
      "options": ["Pizza", "Croissant", "Fries", "Tacos"],
      "correctAnswer": "Fries",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which beverage is known as the 'champagne of tea'?",
      "options": ["Green Tea", "Oolong Tea", "Darjeeling Tea", "Chamomile Tea"],
      "correctAnswer": "Darjeeling Tea",
      "category": "food"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of independent India?",
      "options": [
        "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Sardar Patel",
        "Subhas Chandra Bose"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "When did India gain independence from British rule?",
      "options": ["1942", "1945", "1947", "1950"],
      "correctAnswer": "1947",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was known as the 'Iron Man of India'?",
      "options": [
        "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Sardar Patel",
        "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Subhas Chandra Bose"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Sardar Patel",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which empire was founded by Babur?",
      "options": [
        "Maurya Empire",
        "Gupta Empire",
        "Mughal Empire",
        "Chola Empire"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Mughal Empire",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who led the Dandi March in 1930?",
      "options": [
        "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Bhagat Singh",
        "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Subhas Chandra Bose"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Indian queen was involved in the First War of Independence in 1857?",
      "options": [
        "Rani Lakshmibai",
        "Noor Jahan",
        "Razia Sultan",
        "Mumtaz Mahal"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Rani Lakshmibai",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the capital of India before New Delhi?",
      "options": ["Chennai", "Mumbai", "Kolkata", "Bangalore"],
      "correctAnswer": "Kolkata",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the last Governor-General of independent India?",
      "options": [
        "Lord Mountbatten",
        "C. Rajagopalachari",
        "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Sardar Patel"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "C. Rajagopalachari",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which famous leader gave the slogan 'Do or Die'?",
      "options": [
        "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Bhagat Singh",
        "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Sardar Patel"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Mahatma Gandhi",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who founded the Indian National Congress in 1885?",
      "options": [
        "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
        "A. O. Hume",
        "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Lala Lajpat Rai"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "A. O. Hume",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which event is known as the 'Jallianwala Bagh Massacre'?",
      "options": [
        "Bombay Mutiny",
        "Partition of Bengal",
        "Amritsar Massacre",
        "Salt Satyagraha"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Amritsar Massacre",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first woman to be the President of India?",
      "options": [
        "Pratibha Patil",
        "Indira Gandhi",
        "Sonia Gandhi",
        "Sarojini Naidu"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Pratibha Patil",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Indian leader was popularly called 'Netaji'?",
      "options": [
        "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Bhagat Singh",
        "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Jawaharlal Nehru"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first Indian to win the Nobel Prize?",
      "options": [
        "C. V. Raman",
        "Rabindranath Tagore",
        "Mother Teresa",
        "Hargobind Khorana"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Rabindranath Tagore",
      "category": "history"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the only country to have won all ICC Men's World Cups in all three formats?",
      "options": ["Australia", "India", "England", "West Indies"],
      "correctAnswer": "India",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the captain of the Indian cricket team that won the 1983 World Cup?",
      "options": [
        "Sunil Gavaskar",
        "Kapil Dev",
        "Ravi Shastri",
        "Dilip Vengsarkar"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Kapil Dev",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the trophy awarded to the winner of a Test series between Australia and England?",
      "options": [
        "Border-Gavaskar Trophy",
        "The Ashes",
        "Pataudi Trophy",
        "Chappell-Hadlee Trophy"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The Ashes",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who holds the record for the fastest century in ODI cricket?",
      "options": [
        "Chris Gayle",
        "AB de Villiers",
        "Virat Kohli",
        "Sachin Tendulkar"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "AB de Villiers",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Indian cricketer is known as the 'Master Blaster'?",
      "options": [
        "Rahul Dravid",
        "Sourav Ganguly",
        "Sachin Tendulkar",
        "MS Dhoni"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Sachin Tendulkar",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which team won the first IPL tournament in 2008?",
      "options": [
        "Chennai Super Kings",
        "Rajasthan Royals",
        "Mumbai Indians",
        "Kolkata Knight Riders"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Rajasthan Royals",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which cricketer has the most Test wickets as of 2024?",
      "options": [
        "Shane Warne",
        "James Anderson",
        "Anil Kumble",
        "Muttiah Muralitharan"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Muttiah Muralitharan",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which country won the ICC Men's T20 World Cup in 2021?",
      "options": ["India", "Australia", "Pakistan", "New Zealand"],
      "correctAnswer": "Australia",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the first cricketer to score a double century in ODI cricket?",
      "options": [
        "Virender Sehwag",
        "Rohit Sharma",
        "Sachin Tendulkar",
        "Chris Gayle"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Sachin Tendulkar",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which cricket stadium is the largest in the world by seating capacity?",
      "options": ["Eden Gardens", "MCG", "Narendra Modi Stadium", "Lords"],
      "correctAnswer": "Narendra Modi Stadium",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for scoring 100 runs in cricket?",
      "options": ["Double Century", "Ton", "Century", "Half-Century"],
      "correctAnswer": "Century",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who won the ICC Cricketer of the Year award in 2021?",
      "options": ["Joe Root", "Babar Azam", "Kane Williamson", "Pat Cummins"],
      "correctAnswer": "Joe Root",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Indian bowler has taken the most wickets in IPL history?",
      "options": [
        "Jasprit Bumrah",
        "Harbhajan Singh",
        "Amit Mishra",
        "Lasith Malinga"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Amit Mishra",
      "category": "cricket"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the developer behind the JavaScript programming language?",
      "options": [
        "Brendan Eich",
        "James Gosling",
        "Guido van Rossum",
        "Linus Torvalds"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Brendan Eich",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the main use of the Python programming language?",
      "options": [
        "Mobile App Development",
        "Web Development",
        "Game Development",
        "Automation and Data Science"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Automation and Data Science",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which company developed the Swift programming language?",
      "options": ["Microsoft", "Google", "Apple", "Facebook"],
      "correctAnswer": "Apple",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "In computing, what does 'HTML' stand for?",
      "options": [
        "Hyper Text Markup Language",
        "Hyperlinks and Text Markup Language",
        "Home Tool Markup Language",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Hyper Text Markup Language",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which database is known for its horizontal scalability and flexibility?",

      "options": ["MySQL", "PostgreSQL", "MongoDB", "SQLite"],
      "correctAnswer": "MongoDB",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which company is the parent of the Android operating system?",
      "options": ["Apple", "Google", "Microsoft", "Samsung"],
      "correctAnswer": "Google",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which programming language is known as the language of the web?",
      "options": ["Python", "Java", "JavaScript", "PHP"],
      "correctAnswer": "JavaScript",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the role of a compiler in programming?",
      "options": [
        "To execute code",
        "To interpret code",
        "To convert high-level code to machine code",
        "To debug code"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "To convert high-level code to machine code",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a front-end JavaScript framework?",
      "options": ["Node.js", "Django", "React", "Laravel"],
      "correctAnswer": "React",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which programming language is known for its performance and use in system programming?",
      "options": ["Python", "Ruby", "C", "JavaScript"],
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the `Context API` manage in React?",
      "options": ["State", "Props", "Events", "Routes"],
      "correctAnswer": "State",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which protocol is commonly used for secure communication over the internet?",
      "options": ["FTP", "HTTP", "HTTPS", "SMTP"],
      "correctAnswer": "HTTPS",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a relational database management system?",
      "options": ["MongoDB", "Redis", "PostgreSQL", "Neo4j"],
      "correctAnswer": "PostgreSQL",
      "category": "tech"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which programming paradigm focuses on using functions to build programs?",
      "options": [
        "Functional Programming",
        "Object-Oriented Programming",
        "Procedural Programming",
        "Declarative Programming"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Functional Programming",
      "category": "tech"
    }
  ]
}
export default questionnaire;